Guide to the Helen and Kurt Wolff Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1903-1994; Series I; 18.97' (46 boxes)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Rascher Verlag, 1952-66 (Box 36, Folder 1096)
      Includes copies of letters from Rascher Verlag to S. Fischer Verlag, Franz Beidler, C. G. Jung, Walther Niehus, Bernhard Peyer, and others
    - Rawicz, Piotr, 1961-64 (Box 36, Folder 1097)
    - Read, Herbert [Edward?], 1959-61, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1098)
    - Reclam-Verlag, 1992 (Box 36, Folder 1099)
    - The Reader's Digest, 1967-82 (Box 36, Folder 1100)
    - Reder, Georg, 1961 (Box 36, Folder 1101)
    - Regendanz, Guido, 1964-66 (Box 36, Folder 1102)
    - Reich, Tova, 1987 Jan 15 (Box 36, Folder 1103)
    - Reich, Willi, 1960-65 (Box 36, Folder 1104)
    - Reichl, Ernst, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 1105)
    - Reif, Adelbert, 1979 Jan 9 (Box 36, Folder 1106)
    - Reif-Lehrer, Liane, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 1107)
    - Reimann, Hans, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 1108)
    - Reinhardt, Elly, 1960-63 (Box 36, Folder 1109)
    - Reinhold, H. A. [(Hans Ansgar)?], 1959-64 (Box 36, Folder 1110)
    - Reis, Walter J., 1982-83 (Box 36, Folder 1111)
    - Remak, Joachim, 1967 (Box 36, Folder 1112)
    - Renault, Mary, 1960-62, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1113)
    - Replansky, Naomi, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 1114)
    - Rewald, John, 1961-63 (Box 36, Folder 1115)
    - Rhoda Weyr Agency, 1991-92 (Box 36, Folder 1116)
    - Richter, Hans, 1963, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 1117)
    - Richter, Rudolf, 1961 (Box 36, Folder 1118)
    - Ried, Tessa, 1986-89, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1119)
    - Rietzschel, Thomas, 1984-88 (Box 36, Folder 1120)
    - Rinaldo, Angelo, 1985 Jul 22 (Box 36, Folder 1121)
    - Rivers, Mrs. Henry E., 1965 (Box 36, Folder 1122)
    - Rizzoli Bookstore, 1978, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1123)
    - Robbins, David, 1987-94 (Box 36, Folder 1124-1125)
    - Rochlin, Harriet
    - Roden, E. J. B. von, 1948 (Box 37, Folder 1126)
    - Rogers, Deborah [D.?], 1982 Sep 21 (Box 37, Folder 1127)
    - Rolo, Charles [James?], 1953, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1128)
    - Romanowiczowa, Zofia, 1962-65, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1129)
    - Rosenhaupt, Hans
    - Rosenthal, Arthur, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 1130)
    - Rosenthal, Otto, 1964 Jun (Box 37, Folder 1131)
    - Rosenzweig, Efraim Michael, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 1132)
    - Rosin, Katharine, 1979, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 1133)
    - Ross, Nancy Wilson, 1975 Feb 16 (Box 37, Folder 1134)
    - Ross, Norman, 1958 Nov 5 (Box 37, Folder 1135)
    - Rothe, Martha, 1979, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 1136)
    - Rottensteiner, Franz, 1981-85 (Box 37, Folder 1137)
    - Rougemont, Denis de, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1138)
    - Routledge & Kegan Paul, 1947-71 (Box 37, Folder 1139-1140)
    - Rowohlt (Firm), 1951-69 (Box 37, Folder 1141)
    - Ruben, Margot, 1959-63 (Box 37, Folder 1142)
    - Rubenstein, Carol, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 1143)
    - Rudnicki, Adolf, 1962, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1144)
    - Ruge, Gerd, 1958-61 (Box 37, Folder 1145)
    - Ruhm von Oppen, Beate, 1965-89 (Box 37, Folder 1146)
    - Runciman, Steven, Sir, 1965 (Box 37, Folder 1147)
    - Russell, Pamela Redford, 1982-83 (Box 37, Folder 1148)
    - Russell & Volkening, Inc., 1964-67 (Box 37, Folder 1149)
    - Rütten & Loening, 1965-66 (Box 37, Folder 1150)
    - Rye, Robert, 1965 (Box 37, Folder 1151)
    - "S" General, 1954-91, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1152-1153)
    - S. Fischer Verlag, 1958-90, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1154-1157)
      Includes copy of letter from Fischer to Ann Slater
    - Saggiatore (Firm), 1967-68 (Box 37, Folder 1158)
    - Saint-John Perse, 1943 May 19 (Box 37, Folder 1159)
      Copy of letter from Kurt Wolff
    - Salemson, Harold J., 1983 (Box 37, Folder 1160)
    - Salisbury, Harrison, 1959-61 (Box 37, Folder 1161)
    - Salomon, Paula; Salomon, A., 1961-62, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1162)
    - Salter, Stefan, 1976-83, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1163)
    - Salys, Rima, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 1164)
      Includes printout of sample translation
    - Salzmann, Karl H., 1959-61 (Box 37, Folder 1165)
    - Samuelson, François [Marie?], 1984, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 1166)
    - Sanders, Ivan, 1981-86 (Box 37, Folder 1167)
    - Saner, Hans, 1970-92, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1168)
    - Sasaki, Ruth Fuller, 1959-67, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1169-1171)
      Includes correspondence with Eleanor Gamer, Gallimard (Firm), and Pollock & Stein
    - Saturday Review, 1953 Dec (Box 38, Folder 1172)
    - Sauerländer, Wolfgang, 1952-77 (Box 38, Folder 1173-1180)
      Includes copy of letter to Sauerländer from Richard Hull
    - Sauerländer, Wolfgang; Wachstein-Sauerländer, Beate, 1977, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1181)
    - Schabert, Kyrill, 1933-57 (Box 38, Folder 1182-1185)
      See also: Pantheon Books, Boxes 33-34, folders 994-1025
    - Schabert, Kyrill, 1958-60, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1186-1188)
    - Schaffenburg, Carlos A., 1968-69 (Box 39, Folder 1189)
    - Schatzki, Walter, 1960-61 (Box 39, Folder 1190)
    - Scheer, George F., 1959 (Box 39, Folder 1191)
    - Scher, Steven P. (Steven Paul), 1988 May 10 (Box 39, Folder 1192)
    - Scherer, George A. C., n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1193)
    - Scherman, Harry, 1960, 1963 (Box 39, Folder 1194)
    - Schick, Paul, 1960, 1962 (Box 39, Folder 1195)
    - Schiff, Stacey, 1990, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 1196)
    - Schiffrin, André, 1962-91, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1197)
      Includes letter from Schiffrin to Miklos Harasti
    - Schillemeit, Jost, 1987-88 (Box 39, Folder 1198)
    - Schiller-Nationalmuseum, 1962-93 (Box 39, Folder 1199-1201)
    - Schirach, Henriette von, 1967 Sep (Box 39, Folder 1202)
    - Schirmer, Eva, 1982 Sep 3 (Box 39, Folder 1203)
    - Schirmer, Horst, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 1204)
    - Schirmer, Rudolf, 1982-83 (Box 39, Folder 1205)
    - Schmeichel-Falkenberg, Beate, 1990-93 (Box 39, Folder 1206)
    - Schmidt, Arno, 1990 Sep (Box 39, Folder 1207)
      Letter from Haffmans Verlag
    - Schmidt-Glassner, Helga, 1948 (Box 39, Folder 1208)
    - Schmitz, Dagmar, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 1209)
    - Schneider, Deborah, 1991 Sep 19 (Box 39, Folder 1210)
    - Schneider, Wilhelm Michael, 1962 Jun 18 (Box 39, Folder 1211)
    - Schocken, Dora, 1986-93 (Box 39, Folder 1212)
    - Schocken Books, 1959-71 (Box 39, Folder 1213)
    - Schoeck, Helmut, 1969-83 (Box 39, Folder 1214)
      Includes third-party correspondence between Schoek and the William Volker Fund
    - Scholem, Gershom [Gerhard?], 1979 Apr 19 (Box 39, Folder 1215)
    - Schroeter, Goldmark & Bender, 1982-83 (Box 39, Folder 1216)
    - Schulman, Arlene, 1983 Aug 30 (Box 39, Folder 1217)
    - Schumann, Reinhold, 1985 Jan 15 (Box 39, Folder 1218)
    - Schuyler, Steven, 1977-93, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1219)
    - Schwerin, Christoph, 1964, 1970 (Box 39, Folder 1220)
    - Schwersky, Uwe, 1984 Jun 24 (Box 39, Folder 1221)
    - Scopazzi, Elizabeth-Mary, 1959 (Box 39, Folder 1222)
    - Secker & Warburg, 1960-84 (Box 39, Folder 1223-1225)
    - Seelig, Carl, 1960-61 (Box 39, Folder 1226)
    - Sender Freies Berlin, 1960 Jan 27 (Box 40, Folder 1227)
    - Shahar, David, 1926-, 1979-84 (Box 40, Folder 1228)
    - Shannon, William [Henry?], 1986 Apr 29 (Box 40, Folder 1229)
    - Shatz, Marshall, 1982 Aug 5 (Box 40, Folder 1230)
    - Sheridan, Alan, 1968-85 (Box 40, Folder 1231)
    - Shrifte, Evelyn, 1988 Nov 30 (Box 40, Folder 1232)
    - Shrifte, Herbert, 1960 (Box 40, Folder 1233)
    - Shrifte, Miriam, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 1234)
    - Sifton, Elizabeth, 1988 Jul 28 (Box 40, Folder 1235)
    - Simenon, Georges; Simenon, Denise, 1963-86 (Box 40, Folder 1236-1243)
      Includes copies of correspondence with the Lucy Kroll Agency, Stanley Elkin, Thérèse de Saint-Phalle, Helena Strassova, and others
    - Simenon, Georges, 1986-91, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1244)
    - Simenon, Pierre, 1989, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1245)
    - Simpson, Jerry H., 1984-89, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1246-1248)
    - Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1992 Jul 21 (Box 40, Folder 1249)
    - Sinha, S. [Prakash?], 1982 (Box 40, Folder 1250)
    - Skelton, Geoffrey, 1982, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 1251)
    - Slater, Ann, 1979-93 (Box 40, Folder 1252)
      See also: S. Fischer Verlag, Box 37, folder 1157
    - Slater, Lydia Pasternak, 1961-65, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1253)
    - Slater, Michael, 1987 Aug 8 (Box 40, Folder 1254)
    - Slater, Nicky, 1961-62, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1255)
    - Slonim, Marc, 1961-62 (Box 40, Folder 1256)
    - Smith, Huston, 1965 (Box 41, Folder 1257)
    - Smith, William Jay, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 1258)
    - Smith College, 1977-80, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1259)
    - Societäts Verlag, 1978, 1981 (Box 41, Folder 1260)
    - Société Nationale de Télévision en Couleur "Antenne 2", 1983 May 26 (Box 41, Folder 1261)
    - Solontaroff, Ted, 1987-91, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1262)
    - Sourian, Peter, 1959-72, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1263)
    - [Spater?], George, 1984 May 23 (Box 41, Folder 1264)
    - Spengler, Oswald, 1917 Apr 12 (Box 41, Folder 1265)
      Transcription of letter from Spengler to Kurt Wolff
    - Sperber, Manès, 1961-64 (Box 41, Folder 1266)
    - Spinosi, Edita, 1986-93 (Box 41, Folder 1267)
    - Spodheim, Renee, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 1268)
    - Stacey, Tom, 1959-61 (Box 41, Folder 1269)
    - Stadelmeyer, Franz, 1958 (Box 41, Folder 1270)
    - Städelsches Kunstinstitut (Frankfurt am Main, Germany), 1962 Jul (Box 41, Folder 1271)
    - Stadtbibliothek Ludwigshafen. Ernst- Bloch-Archiv, 1980 (Box 41, Folder 1272)
    - Stamperia Valdonega, 1959-71 (Box 41, Folder 1273-1275)
      See also: Origo, Iris, Box 31, folder 960
    - Stansbury, Milton, 1965-70 (Box 41, Folder 1276-1277)
    - Steegmuller, Francis, 1984, 1986 (Box 41, Folder 1278)
    - Steidl, 1992-93 (Box 41, Folder 1279)
    - Steingrüssen Verlag, 1961-66 (Box 41, Folder 1280)
    - Steinwachs, Ginka, 1980 (Box 41, Folder 1281)
    - Stephens, Walter, 1993 May 12 (Box 41, Folder 1282)
    - Sterba, Richard F., 1959-63, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1283)
    - Stern, Fritz [Richard?], 1985 May 3 (Box 41, Folder 1284)
    - Steuermann, Edward; Steuermann, Clara, 1959-60, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1285)
    - Stirling, Monica, n.y. Aug 12 (Box 41, Folder 1286)
    - Stockman, Russell, 1989-92 (Box 41, Folder 1287)
    - Stolper, Toni, 1959-60 (Box 41, Folder 1288)
    - Strand, Paul, 1961 (Box 41, Folder 1289)
    - Strassova, Helena, 1960-63, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1290)
      See also: Simenon, Georges, Box, 40 folder 1236
    - Strauss, Herbert, 1978 May 12 (Box 41, Folder 1291)
    - Strecker, Ludwig, 1957 (Box 41, Folder 1292)
    - Streit-Scherz, Rudolf, 1962 (Box 41, Folder 1293)
    - Streuli, Adolf, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 1294)
      Includes copies of letters from Streuli to Rascher Verlag
    - Stryjkowski, Julien, 1968-72 (Box 41, Folder 1295)
    - Stuart, Errett, 1959-62 (Box 41, Folder 1296)
    - Süddeutsche Zeitung, 1979, 1985 (Box 41, Folder 1297)
    - Suhrkamp Verlag, 1961-93, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1298-1299)
    - Sussman, Aaron, 1959-73, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1300)
    - Susan P. Urstadt, Inc., 1985, 1988 (Box 42, Folder 1301)
    - Suzuki, Daisetz Teitaro, 1870-1966, 1960 Jan (Box 42, Folder 1302)
    - Swan, Jon, 1968 (Box 42, Folder 1303)
    - Sweetman, David, 1992 Jul 17 (Box 42, Folder 1304)
    - Szasz, Kathleen, 1963-65 (Box 42, Folder 1305)
    - Szladits, Lola [L.?], [1983?] (Box 42, Folder 1306)
    - "T" General, 1960-86 (Box 42, Folder 1307)
    - Taplinger Publishing Co. Inc., 1982-83 (Box 42, Folder 1308)
    - Tau, Max, 1960-63 (Box 42, Folder 1309)
    - Taubert, Sigfred, 1959-63 (Box 42, Folder 1310)
    - Tavistock Publications, 1963-65 (Box 42, Folder 1311)
    - Thames and Hudson, 1961-68, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1312-1313)
    - Theegarten-Schlotterer, Corry, 1987-93 (Box 42, Folder 1314)
    - Thorton, Thomas, 1986-87, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1315)
    - Thorwald, Jürgen, 1957-87 (Box 42, Folder 1316)
      Includes copy of letter from Thorwald to Droemersche Verlagsanstalt
    - Tillich, Paul, 1962-63 (Box 42, Folder 1317)
    - Time, 1964-65 (Box 42, Folder 1318)
    - Toffler, Alvin, 1982 Nov 2 (Box 42, Folder 1319)
    - Torberg, Friedrich, 1959-62 (Box 42, Folder 1320)
    - Tormin, Dietlinde, 1984-93 (Box 42, Folder 1321)
    - Trabitzsch, Michael, 1988 Jul 22 (Box 42, Folder 1322)
    - Translation
      See: Columbia University. Translation Center, Box 4, folder 159
    - Trask, Willard R. (Willard Ropes), 1964-78, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1323-1326)
    - Trevelyan, Raleigh, 1980 Mar 17 (Box 42, Folder 1327)
    - Treviranus, [Gottfried Reinhold?], [1961?] (Box 42, Folder 1328)
    - Trianon Press, 1962-63 (Box 42, Folder 1329)
    - Tri-quarterly, 1976 Mar 16 (Box 42, Folder 1330)
    - Troschke, Harald von, 1988 (Box 42, Folder 1331)
    - Trowbridge, Clinton, 1982 Nov 15 (Box 42, Folder 1332)
    - Turnell, Martin
      See: Harvill Press, Box 14, folder 476
    - "U" General, 1962-74 (Box 43, Folder 1333)
    - Ulich, Robert, 1944 Feb 15 (Box 43, Folder 1334)
    - Ullstein GmbH, 1969 Aug 29 (Box 43, Folder 1335)
    - Ulmer, Anne [Close?], 1984 (Box 43, Folder 1336)
    - Union de Banques Suisses, 1962 Jun 8 (Box 43, Folder 1337)
    - United States. Embassy (Soviet Union), 1981 Dec 8 (Box 43, Folder 1338)
    - United States. Embassy (Switzerland), 1963 (Box 43, Folder 1339)
    - Universität Frankfurt am Main, 1986 Feb 6 (Box 43, Folder 1340)
    - University of California Press, 1966-67, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1341)
    - University of Chicago. Press, 1982-92, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1342)
      Includes copies of correspondence with Michael Ermarth
    - University of Michigan, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1343)
    - University of Pennsylvania. Press, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 1344)
    - University Press of New England, 1983-92, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1345)
    - "V" General, 1963-91, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1346)
    - Vallecchi Editore, 1962 (Box 43, Folder 1347)
    - Van Loewen, Jan, 1963-68 (Box 43, Folder 1348)
    - Vaughan, Samuel S., 1990 (Box 43, Folder 1349)
    - Veith, Ilza, 1983, 1988 (Box 43, Folder 1350)
    - Veltheim, Adelheid von, 1982 (Box 43, Folder 1351)
    - Vennewitz, Leila, 1983-88 (Box 43, Folder 1352)
    - Verlag Bruno Cassirer, 1961 Nov (Box 43, Folder 1353)
    - Verlag C. H. Beck, 1961-63 (Box 43, Folder 1354)
    - Verlag Heinrich Scheffler, 1960-92, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1355-1357)
      Includes copies of correspondence between VHS and Klaus W. Jonas and Erika Mann
    - Verlag Herder, 1960-86 (Box 43, Folder 1358)
    - Verlag Kiepenheuer & Witsch, 1961-75 (Box 43, Folder 1359)
    - Verlag Klaus Wagenbach, 1962-93, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1360-1364)
    - Verlag Kurt Desch, 1962-63 (Box 43, Folder 1365)
    - Victor Gollanz Ltd., 1960-66 (Box 43, Folder 1366)
    - Villeneuve, Roland, 1961-62 (Box 43, Folder 1367)
    - Vincent, Maurice, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 1368)
    - Vinçon, Hartmut, 1988-89 (Box 43, Folder 1369)
    - Vitelli, Tom, 1985 May (Box 43, Folder 1370)
    - Vittorio Klostermann (Firm), 1961-90 (Box 43, Folder 1371)
    - Vogel, Ilse Margaret, 1990 (Box 43, Folder 1372)
    - Vogüé, Jean de, 1983-84, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1373)
    - Voigt, Klaus, 1982-88, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1374)
    - Vorms, Pierre, 1961 (Box 43, Folder 1375)
    - "W" General, 1948-92, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1376-1377)
    - W. W. Norton & Company, 1958-80 (Box 44, Folder 1378)
    - Wade, Mason, 1982 Aug (Box 44, Folder 1379)
    - Walker, John, 1961-62 (Box 44, Folder 1380)
    - Walter, Otto, 1958 Jun (Box 44, Folder 1381)
    - Walter-Verlag AG Olten, 1960-87 (Box 44, Folder 1382)
    - Ward, Aileen, 1982 Sep 23 (Box 44, Folder 1383)
    - Wargon, Allan, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 1384)
    - Warren, Dorothy, 1979-87 (Box 44, Folder 1385)
      Includes photocopy of letter from Iris Origo to Warren and carbon of letter from Warren to John Murray
    - Washington Resources, Inc., 1986-88, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1386)
    - Wasmuth, Günther, 1959-60 (Box 44, Folder 1387)
    - Wasson, Gordon, 1951-85 (Box 44, Folder 1388)
    - Watkins, Renee, 1965 Oct 28 (Box 44, Folder 1389)
    - Watson, Nancy, 1982-83 (Box 44, Folder 1390)
    - Watts, Allan, 1915-1973, 1947-67 (Box 44, Folder 1391)
    - Weaver, William, 1976-86 (Box 44, Folder 1392)
    - Wehdeking, Volker, 1985, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1393)
    - Weigel, Hans, 1985 Mar 7 (Box 44, Folder 1394)
    - Weil, Gotshal & Manges, 194-61 (Box 44, Folder 1395)
    - Weinberg, Robert, 1951-61, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1396)
    - Weinke, Wilfried, 1992-93 (Box 44, Folder 1397)
    - Weiss, Jiri, 1974 Apr 28 (Box 44, Folder 1398)
    - Wells, Leon [Weliczker?], 1991 (Box 44, Folder 1399)
    - Welsh, David, 1962-70 (Box 44, Folder 1400)
    - Werfel, Franz, 1930 (Box 44, Folder 1401)
      Includes carbon and transcription of letters from Werfel
    - Wettlin, Margaret, 1981-82 (Box 44, Folder 1402)
    - Wheeler, Barbara, 1979, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1403)
    - Wheelis, Allen, 1981-92 (Box 44, Folder 1404)
    - Wheelis, Ilse, 1982-86 (Box 44, Folder 1405)
    - Wickert, Erwin, 1985 Jan 22 (Box 44, Folder 1406)
    - Wiegenstein, Roland H., 1988 (Box 44, Folder 1407)
    - Wieskerstrauch. Liz, 1991-92 (Box 44, Folder 1408)
    - Wilder, Isabel, 1963-64 (Box 44, Folder 1409)
    - Wilder, Lucy, 1983 Jun 8 (Box 44, Folder 1410)
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1959-66 (Box 44, Folder 1411)
    - Wiles, Peter, 1967-71 (Box 44, Folder 1412)
    - Wilhelm, Hellmut, 1958-65 (Box 44, Folder 1413)
    - Wilhelm Goldmann Verlag, 1959 (Box 44, Folder 1414)
    - Wilkins, Eithne, 1964-66 (Box 44, Folder 1415)
    - Wilkins, Sophie, 1974 Apr 8 (Box 44, Folder 1416)
    - Wilkinson, Burke, 1982-91, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1417-1418)
    - William Collins Sons & Co., 1958-61 (Box 44, Folder 1419-1422)
      Includes carbon of letter to Bernhard Peyer
    - William Collins Sons & Co., 1961-82, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1423-1428)
    - William Morris Agency, 1984 (Box 45, Folder 1429)
    - Willson, A. Leslie (Amos Leslie), 1985 Feb 13 (Box 45, Folder 1430)
    - Wilson, Edmund, 1958-67 (Box 45, Folder 1431)
    - Winchell, Margaret, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 1432)
    - Winston, Richard; Winston, Clara, 1958-82, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1433)
      See also: Jaffé, Aniela, Box 19, folder 598
    - Winternitz, Emanuel, 1967 (Box 45, Folder 1434)
    - WNET (Television Station: New York, N.Y.), 1987-89 (Box 45, Folder 1435)
    - Wohanka, George, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 1436)
    - Woldemar Klein Verlag, 1960-62 (Box 45, Folder 1437)
    - Wolff, Alexander, 1979, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1438)
    - Wolff, Konrad, 1981-82 (Box 45, Folder 1439)
    - Wolff, Paul, 1948 (Box 45, Folder 1440)
    - Woodrow Wilson National Fellowship Foundation, 1985 Oct (Box 45, Folder 1441)
    - Woods, John E., 1981-82 (Box 45, Folder 1442)
      Includes translation of "Lake Scenes with Pocahontas" by Arno Schmidt
    - Wright, Ellen, 1966, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 1443)
    - The Writer's Digest, 1979 Jan (Box 45, Folder 1444)
    - Yale University. Art Gallery, 1962 (Box 45, Folder 1445)
    - Yale University. Library, 1948-63 (Box 45, Folder 1446)
    - Young, Barbara, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 1447)
    - Young-Bruehl, Elisabeth, 1980 Jul 30 (Box 45, Folder 1448)
    - Yourcenar, Marguerite, 1968 Apr 21 (Box 45, Folder 1449)
    - "Z" General, 1955-90 (Box 45, Folder 1450)
    - Zahrnt, H., 1968 (Box 45, Folder 1451)
    - Zantop, Susanne, 1991 May 14 (Box 45, Folder 1452)
    - Zara, Louis, 1967 Feb 24 (Box 45, Folder 1453)
    - Zaroff, Anne, 1980-82, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1454)
    - Die Zeit, 1966, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 1455)
    - Ziegfeld, Richard, 1979-84, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1456)
    - Ziolkowski, Theodore
    - Zohn, Harry, 1960, 1987 (Box 45, Folder 1457)
      Includes photocopy of letter from Zohn to Alfred Ivry
    - Zokeisha Publications, 1963-65 (Box 45, Folder 1458)
    - Zolla, Elémire, 1988 Mar 22 (Box 45, Folder 1459)
    - Zuckmayer, Carl, 1966-71 (Box 45, Folder 1460)
    - Zweig, A., 1968 (Box 45, Folder 1461)
    - Zwemmer's (Firm), 1961-62 (Box 45, Folder 1462)
    - Unidentified
      - First names only, 1955-84, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1463)
      - Illegible signatures, 1903-83, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1464)
      - Unsigned, 1960-77 (Box 46, Folder 1465)
      - Letters from Helen and Kurt Wolff to recipients with first names only, 1955-82 (Box 46, Folder 1466)
      - Letters from Helen and Kurt Wolff to unidentified recipients, 1955-77, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1467)
    - Empty envelopes, 1974 Dec 14 (Box 46, Folder 1468)
  - THIRD-PARTY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Arthur Andersen & Co. to Fried, Frank, Harris Shriver & Jacobsen, 1975 Jun 19 (Box 46, Folder 1469)
    - Cleary, Gottlieb, Friendly & Hamilton to Nathan Levin, 1956 Apr 19 (Box 46, Folder 1470)
    - Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague to Adolf and Frieda Busch, 1940-44 (Box 46, Folder 1471)
      Copies of letters
    - Curtis Brown Ltd. to Harvill Press, 1952 Jul 30 (Box 46, Folder 1472)
    - Fahlke, Eberhard to Uwe Johnson Archiv, 1992 Jan 7 (Box 46, Folder 1473)
    - Georges Borchardt, Inc. to Jerry H. Simpson, 1989 Sep 6 (Box 46, Folder 1474)
    - Grass, Günter to Anna Seghers, 1961 Aug 14 (Box 46, Folder 1475)
      Photocopy of translation
    - Hauli, Gejza to Random House, 1958 Sep 22 (Box 46, Folder 1476)
    - Jelenski, Konstanty A. (Konstanty Aleksander) to Le Figaro Littéraire, 1969 Jan 9 (Box 46, Folder 1477)
      Photocopy
    - Noëlle, Maria to Mohrbooks, 1982 Oct 15 (Box 46, Folder 1478)
    - [Pasternak, Boris Leonidovich?] to unidentified, 1959-60 (Box 46, Folder 1479)
    - Schlechta, Karl to Carl Hanser Verlag, 1962 Nov 23 (Box 46, Folder 1480)
    - Svensson, George to Feltrinelli editore, 1958 Oct 31 (Box 46, Folder 1481)
    - Uwe Johnson Archiv to Eberhard Fahlke, 1991 Dec 11 (Box 46, Folder 1482)
- Kurt Wolff Verlag Papers, 1913-1931; Series II; 0.21' (1 box)
  Series IV, Kurt Wolff Verlag Papers, is arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Bookmark, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1483)
  - Clippings, 1914-31 (Box 47, Folder 1484)
  - Contract, 1922 Jul 14 (Box 47, Folder 1485)
  - Design for logo, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1486)
  - Financial statements, [1925-28] (Box 47, Folder 1487)
  - Invitation, 1925 Feb 14 (Box 47, Folder 1488)
  - Letter-head, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1489)
  - List of titles, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1490)
  - Postcard, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1491)
  - Publicity, [1913?] (Box 47, Folder 1492)
  - Signed card, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1493)
- Pantheon Books Papers, 1933-1963; Series III; 2.29' (6 boxes)
  Series III, Pantheon Books Papers, is organized into three subseries: Writings, Financial and Legal Records, and Other Papers.
  - WRITINGS
    - Adamson, Joy
      - Born Free
        - Publicity, 1960 (Box 48, Folder 1494)
    - Berg, Marina de
      - Carnet de Trente Veilles
        - Reader report, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1495)
    - Broch, Hermann
      - The Death of Virgil
        - [Reader report?], n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1496)
        - Publicity, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1497)
    - Duggan, Alfred Leo
      - The Cunning of the Dove
        - Publicity, 1960 (Box 48, Folder 1498)
    - Dumoulin, Heinrich
      - A History of Zen Buddhism
        - Reviews, 1963 Apr 21 (Box 48, Folder 1499)
    - Fallada, Hans
      - That Rascal Fridolin
        - Reviews, 1959 (Box 48, Folder 1500)
    - Fletcher, David
      - The Village of Hidden Wishes
        - Reviews, 1960 May 22 (Box 48, Folder 1501)
    - Grass, Günter
      - The Tin Drum
        First published as Blechtrommel (Darmstadt: Luchterhand, 1959)
        - Proof of corrections, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1502)
        - Reader report, 1959 Aug 27 (Box 48, Folder 1503)
    - Jouhandreau, Marcel
      - Chroniques Maritales
        - Printed version, corrected, 1944 (Box 48, Folder 1504)
      - Marcel et Élise
        - Drafts, preface, corrected, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1505)
      - Monsieur Godeau Marié
        - Printed version, corrected, 1933 (Box 48, Folder 1506)
    - Jung, C. G. (Carl Gustav)
      - Memories, Dreams, Reflections